novafm.com.au 2012-03-01

# Privacy Statement - NovaFM

Privacy Statement

Journalism exception

* * *

**DMG Radio (Australia) Pty Ltd  
Web Site Privacy Policy  
13 January 2011**

dmg Radio (Australia) Pty Ltd ABN 75 093 553 989 ( **dmg** ) owns and operates the Nova network of radio stations around Australia covering Nova 106.9 in Brisbane, Nova 96.9 in Sydney, Nova 100.3 in Melbourne, Nova 91.9 in Adelaide and Nova 93.7 in Perth. dmg also owns and operates Classic Rock 95.3FM Sydney, Classic Rock 91.5FM Melbourne, Radio FIVEaa in Adelaide, Star 104.5 in Gosford on the NSW central coast and the digital DAB+ stations Novanation and Koffee. dmg and each of its radio stations is bound by this Privacy Statement.

 **1 Protecting your privacy**  
1.1 dmg and each of its radio stations is committed to protecting your privacy.  
1.2 We are bound by the National Privacy Principles under the Commonwealth Privacy Act, except in relation to our activities carried out in the course of journalism. The National Privacy Principles and this Privacy Statement set out the standards of protection you can expect in respect of your personal information.  
1.3 Set out below is the information which we are required under the National Privacy Principles to give you, as a user of this web site or any of our station web sites. We recommend that you keep a copy of this information for future reference.  
1.4 By accessing and using our web site or any of our station web sites or by submitting information to us, you consent to us using and disclosing your personal information in the ways described in this Privacy Statement.

**2 Journalism exception**  
2.1 Even though the National Privacy Principles do not apply to our activities carried out in the course of journalism, we are still committed to protecting your privacy when carrying on such activities.  
2.2 We therefore publicly commit to comply with the dmg Journalism Privacy Standards when engaged in journalism activities. To view a copy of these standards, click on the menu item on this page.

**3 About us**  
3.1 dmg is responsible for managing the entire Nova and Classic Rock radio networks, Radio FIVEaa, Star 104.5 and the digital DAB+ stations Novanation and Koffee. dmg’s main place of business is located at Level 5, 75 Hindmarsh Square, Adelaide, SA, 5000.  
3.2 Our radio stations are responsible for their own web sites. Among other things, our stations provide the music you can listen to on their web sites and arrange competitions you can enter on them.

**Our stations main places of business are located at**

**Nova 96.9**  
Level 5  
33 Saunders Street  
PYRMONT NSW 2009

| 

**Nova 100.3**  
Level 2  
678 Victoria Street  
RICHMOND VIC 3121  
  
---|---  
  
**Nova 106.9**  
Level 3  
130 Commercial Road  
TENERIFFE QLD 4005

| 

**Nova 91.9**  
Level 3  
75 Hindmarsh Square  
ADELAIDE SA 5000  
  
**Nova 93.7**  
Level 1  
464 Hay Street  
SUBIACO WA 6008

|    
  
**Classic Rock 95.3FM  
** Level 3  
33 Saunders Street  
PYRMONT NSW 2009

| 

**Classic Rock 91.5FM  
** Level 2  
678 Victoria Street  
RICHMOND VIC 3121  
  
**Star104.5**  
Level 1  
4 Ilya Avenue  
ERINA NSW 2250

| 

**FIVE aa**  
Level 4  
75 Hindmarsh Square  
ADELAIDE SA 5000  
  
**Novanation**  
Level 3  
130 Commercial Road  
TENERIFFE QLD 4005 | **Koffee**  
Level 3  
130 Commercial Road  
TENERIFFE QLD 4005  
  
**4 Your personal information**  
4.1 We may hold a variety of personal information about you, including your name, date of birth, your current and previous addresses, your phone number, e-mail address, and certain details about your personal interests.  
4.2 Occasionally, you may need to give us personal information about other people - for example, your family or other authorised representatives. If so, we rely on you to tell those individuals that you are giving their personal information to us.  
4.3 If you choose not to give personal information to us, we may not be able to provide you with access to some or all of the web sites or to our other products and services.

**5 How we collect personal information**  
5.1 We may collect personal information from you in a number of ways, including:

  * directly from you - for example, when you send us an email, apply to register as a member of any of our web sites, or complete and submit an online form;
  * from third parties - for example, our related companies, credit reporting agencies or your representatives;
  * from publicly available sources; and
  * when legally required to do so.

**6 How we collect personal information from our Web Sites**  
6.1 We may also collect personal information about you when you use and access our web sites.  
6.2 One of the ways we may collect information about you is through the use of “cookie”. A cookie is a small text file that the web site may place on your computer. Cookies may be used, among other things, to track the pages you have visited, to remember your preferences and to store personal information about you.  
6.3 You can adjust your Internet browser to disable cookies or to warn you when cookies are being used. However, if you disable cookies, you may not be able to access certain areas of our web sites or take advantage of the improved web site experience that cookies offer.  
6.4 When you visit our web sites, our web servers may record other information about or relating to you, such as the time and date of your visit or the IP address assigned to the computer you are using to access the web site. In many cases, we cannot and do not use this information to identify you personally - rather, we simply use this information to track and improve the performance of the web sites.

**7 How we use your personal information**  
7.1 Your personal information may be used by us in a number of ways, including:

  * to give you access to our web sites and to the content and other things on the web sites;
  * to enter you into competitions and promotions;
  * to market our products and services (or those of other people) to you, including by email;
  * to inform you of changes to our web sites, or our business, or to the content and other things available from the web sites;
  * to conduct appropriate checks for credit-worthiness and for fraud; and
  * our internal business purposes - for example, to research and develop the web sites and our other products and services.  

7.2 If you do not want us to use your personal information for direct marketing purposes, please contact our Privacy Officer by sending an email to Sarah Tinsley, dmg Corporate Counsel, [stinsley@dmgradio.com.au](mailto:stinsley@dmgradio.com.au)

**  
8 When we disclose your personal information**  
8.1 We may disclose your personal information to each other, to our related companies and to various outside organisations (some of which may be located in foreign countries). Except as permitted under the National Privacy Principles, we will only disclose your personal information for one of the purposes set out in part 7.1 above.  
8.2 Some of the outside organisations we may disclose your personal information to include:

  * our advertisers and sponsors;
  * other organisations involved in the operation and management of our web sites, including market research companies and IT service providers;
  * your representatives, including your legal advisers;
  * credit reporting and fraud checking agencies;
  * our professional advisers, including our legal advisers and accountants;
  * government and regulatory authorities, including the Australian Communications and Media Authority; and
  * organisations that purchase all or part of our assets or businesses.

8.3 If any of these organisations are located outside Australia, you expressly consent to us disclosing your personal information to those organisations.  
8.4 We take reasonable steps to ensure that each organisation that we disclose your personal information to is committed to protecting your privacy.  
8.5 When you register as a member of any of our web sites, some information about your account (such as your user name) may be publicly available on our web sites when you contribute content to our web sites, or participate in any of our web site forums or chat rooms. If you choose to include any personal information about yourself in any content that you contribute to any of our web sites, that information will be available and accessible to other users of our web sites anywhere in the world.  
8.6 You must not include any personal information about other people in any content that you contribute to any of our web sites, unless such people have expressly consented to you including their personal information in such content and to you providing the content to us for use on our web sites. 

**9 Help us to ensure we hold accurate information**  
9.1 We take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we collect, use and disclose is accurate, complete and up-to-date. However, the accuracy of the information we hold depends to a large extent on the information you provide.  
9.2 Please help us by:

> (a) letting us know if there are any errors in the information we hold about you; and  
>  (b) keeping us up to date with changes to your information, such as changes to your name or address.

9.3 If you are a member, you can access, change and update your membership profile at any time by logging into your membership account via our relevant station’s web site.

**10 How you can access your personal information**  
10.1 You have a right to access your personal information, subject to some exceptions allowed by law. If you would like to do so, please let us know by contacting our Privacy Officer. For security reasons, we may ask you to put your request in writing.  
10.2 We may charge a fee for searching for and providing access to your information.

**11 Preventing unauthorised access to your personal information**  
11.1 We will take reasonable steps to maintain the security of and to prevent unauthorised access to or disclosure of your personal information.  
11.2 However, we do not guarantee that unauthorised access to your personal information will not occur, either during transmission of that information to us or after we receive that information.

**12 Linked sites**  
12.1 Our web sites may contain links to other Internet web sites. These links are provided solely for your convenience.  
12.2 If you submit personal information to or via any linked site, the privacy principles applying to that information will be outside our control. You should therefore check the privacy statement of the linked site before submitting information to or via that site.

**13 Changes to our Privacy Statement**  
13.1 From time to time, we may need to change this Privacy Statement to reflect our changing business practices. We may therefore change this Privacy Statement at any time by posting the changed Privacy Statement on this web site, and by posting a notice to users on the dmg and our radio station homepages stating that a change has occurred.  
13.2 All personal information collected and held by us will be governed by our most recent Privacy Statement, as posted on this web site.

**  
14 How to contact us**  
14.1 If you have any questions in relation to privacy, please contact our Privacy Officer by sending an email to Sarah Tinsley, dmg Corporate Counsel, [stinsley@dmgradio.com.au](mailto:stinsley@dmgradio.com.au). This email address should not be used for general inquiries.  
14.2 If you have a general inquiry relating to any of our station web sites or any of our radio stations, please contact us by sending an email to [executive@dmgradio.com.au](mailto:executive@dmgradio.com.au).  
14.3 If you have a general inquiry relating to the dmg web site or dmg, please contact us by sending an email to [executive@dmgradio.com.au](mailto:executive@dmgradio.com.au).

* * *

**1 Journalism exemption to the Privacy Act**

The Commonwealth Privacy Act seeks to balance the public interest in providing adequate safeguards for the handling of personal information and the public interest in allowing a free flow of information to the public through the media.  
The Privacy Act exempts acts done by a media organisation such as _dmg_ in the course of journalism provided that at the time of the act, the media organisation is publicly committed to observe standards that deal with privacy in the context of the activities of the organisation and those standards are published in writing by the organisation or a person or body representing a class of media organisations.  
 _dmg_ has developed the Journalism Privacy Standards set out in this document and is publicly committed to observe these Standards. Accordingly, _dmg_ is exempt from complying with the National Privacy Principles in respect of its journalism activities.

**2 Definitions**

"Personal information" in these Journalism Privacy Standards means information or an opinion (whether true or not and regardless of its source) about an individual whose identity is apparent or can reasonably be ascertained from the information or opinion.  
"we", "us" and "our" means _dmg_ Radio (Australia) Pty Ltd (ABN 75 093 553 989) and its related bodies corporate and their respective officers and employees.

**3 Application of the Journalism Privacy Standards**

These standards apply to collection, use and disclosure of personal information by us in the course of our journalism activities.

**4 Collection of personal information**

We will collect personal information only where it is in the public interest to do so.  
We will respect an individual's right to protection from unwarranted invasions of privacy.  
Our journalists may collect personal information without revealing their identity where it is in the public interest to do so.  
We will respect the private grief of individuals.

**5 Use of personal information**

Personal information will only be used for the purpose for which it was collected or a directly related and reasonable secondary purpose.  
Personal information obtained by unfair means will not be broadcast or otherwise disclosed unless there are overriding public interest considerations.  
We will not intrude into the privacy of public figures unless the intrusion is related to the individuals' public role or activities or there are overriding public interest considerations.

**6 Quality and accuracy of personal information**

We will take reasonable steps to ensure that personal information we collect, use or disclose is accurate, complete and up-to-date.

**7 Security of personal information**

We will take reasonable steps to protect personal information we hold from misuse and loss and from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure.

**8 Confidential sources**

Where it is lawful to do so, we may refuse to do anything which could reveal the identity of a person who gave us personal information in confidence. Where it is lawful to do so and where there are no overriding public interest considerations, we will attempt to ensure that any personal information which we broadcast or otherwise disclose does not identify the source of the information if the information was provided to us in confidence.

**9 Correction**

Where personal information which is materially inaccurate is broadcast or otherwise disclosed, we will take reasonable steps to rectify the disclosure.

**10 Codes of Practice**

The Commercial Radio Codes of Practice registered by the Australian Broadcasting Authority also impose some relevant privacy obligations on us. We are committed to complying with these Codes of Practice.

**11 Privacy Officer**

If you have any concerns, complaints or questions, please contact our Privacy Officer - [stinsley@dmgradio.com.au](mailto:stinsley@dmgradio.com.au)
